<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Math!</name>
	<author>CrunchyDuck</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.3</li>
		<li>1.4</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<packageId>CrunchyDuck.Math</packageId>
	<description>[h2]What does this mod do?[/h2]
[list]
[*]Ability to perform [b]Math![/b] with a huge range of variables, from "how many pawns have the fast walker trait", to "how much food do our colonists need to eat per day"
[*]Create your own variables to cut down on the amount of [b]Math![/b] you need to do
[*]New field to calculate how much of an item exists - Want you simple meal production to count all meals, not just simple? Use "categories.meals"!
[*]Larger bill details
[*]Robust in-game info button with examples, variables and explanations for using [b]Math![/b]
[/list]
Many features from the mod [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=935982361]Better Workbench Management[/url] have been added, such as:
[list]
[*]Dragging bills to rearrange
[*]Linking [b]any[/b] bills together to match their settings, as well as options to choose what settings are matched.
[*]A button to easily switch between "take to stockpile" and "drop on floor"
[*]Renaming bills!
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]
You can add this to a new save, and you can also remove it from a save. You will get an error the first time you remove the mod, but it won't break your game.
Things from other mods like new foods or weapons will work with this mod.
If a mod changes the UI of the bill menu, it likely won't work with this mod.

[h2]Languages[/h2]
[b]Math![/b] will allow you to use variables in your native language.
However, right now none of my tutorials/explanations are in other languages. I have everything set up to support other languages, but none made yet.
If you speak any language besides English or Spanish and wish to contribute, I'd be happy to discuss it in my Discord.


[b]Links:[/b]
Discord with me and my budderoos: https://discord.gg/hUnEs9ZhwA
Github: https://github.com/CrunchyDuck/Math
NCalc, the math library I use: https://github.com/ncalc/ncalc
donate: I will keep doing what I do regardless of income. https://ko-fi.com/crunchyduck

[b]Credits[/b]
falconne, who made [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=935982361]Better Workbench Management[/url] and its assets.

[img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CrunchyDuck/Math/master/About/licence_image.png[/img]</description>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
		<li>brrainz.harmony</li>
	</loadAfter>
	<incompatibleWith>
	  <li>falconne.BWM</li>
	</incompatibleWith>
</ModMetaData>
